Shashank Singh

Frontend Developer

A Frontend Developer with 3.2 years of experience in web development, working @ **Deloitte India**. A good coder with a solid understanding of algorithms and application architecture fundamentals. A creative, quick adapter, and a product enthusiast, driven by innovation and passionate about solving problems by building products.

Ballia (U.P.), India Work Location - Pune +91-9473722988 singh.shashank2798@gmail.com

Work Experience

Deloitte India - Consultant

October 2022 - PRESENT

Project: Product / Service Management System

Jan 2023 - Present

- Working on application dealing with service and delivery management of the product..
- Using **NgRx**, **Observables**, **Routing Guards**, Reactive Form, etc. in the development of the application.
- Tech-Stack: Angular 12, Typescript, SCSS, Client Frameworks, Java, NodeJs, MSAL Services, MS Azure.

Infosys Limited - Senior Systems Engineer

December 2019 - October 2022

Project: Bidding management System

July 2022 - September 2022

- Re-designed and Optimized whole applications, modified architecture and reduced code and bundle size by 20%.
- **Efficiently managed** a team of 3 system engineers during this project, understood client requirements and **implemented Agile methodology** in the project.
- Tech-Stack: Angular JS, JavaScript, CSS, Shui-framework, Java, SQL.

Project: Idea Management System

August 2021 - June 2022

- Developed a 50-page application for 400k users with reusable components with Common Validations, Notifications and HTTP Interceptors, Functions, Directives, Pipes and Services.
- Implemented **Ag-Grid table and Ag-Grid graph**, added dynamic features like CRUD operation on the row, **runtime update of data**, and complex calculation, which resulted in decrement of load on the backend.
- **Tech-Stack**: Angular 10, Typescript, CSS, Angular Material, .Net, SQL, MS-Azure.

Project: Employee On-Board Portal

Jan 2021 - July 2021

- Created a User-HR chat portal using the features of Mendix and entity-object behaviour.
- Worked with Microflows and Nanoflows to apply validations, functions and authentication on the pages.
- Tech-Stack: Mendix

Project: Internal Company Projects

Dec 2019 - Nov 2020

- Trained on MEAN stack and worked as a maintenance engineer.
- Created Full stack projects Queries & feedback WebApp and Internal Employee Portals, as a trainee.
- Tech-Stack: Angular 8, Typescript, CSS, NgPrime, NodeJs, MongoDB.

Skills

Programming - Angular (2+), AngularJS, TypeScripts, NodeJS, JavaScript, Python.

Familiar with - Agile methodologies, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular-material, Mendix, SQL, MS-Azure (CI/CD), NgPrime, and AgGrid Library.

Awards

Infosys Insta Award for management and performance.

Received an early **promotion**, promoted to **Senior System Engineer**.

Infosys Angular Certified Professional.

Infosys Basic Agile Certified Professional.

Mendix Certified Rapid Developer.

Voluntary worked as Head of Management in education startup Discovery Classes, 2019

Education

B.Tech (2015-2019) - **Mechanical Engineering** with **Honors** from PSIT, Kanpur, U.P.

Social Links

